Kody Samaroo

Edison, NJ, 08817 | (908) 616-2650 | kody.samaroo@gmail.com Github | Blog | LinkedIn

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Software Engineer experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and React frameworks with a background study in Information Technology, Data Analytics and Data Management. As a natural leader and calculated decision maker I have structured databases in order to resourcefully manage IT systems. I am passionate to use new technologies to find simple solutions to analytically make resourceful decisions for complex social problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

AWS | Database Management | Git | Javascript | Postgres | Rails | React with Hooks | Redux | Ruby | SCSS SQL | TypeScript

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Code-Bucket - Github | Website | Demo

Code-Bucket provides an environment to practice web development and experiment with front-end application designs

- Designed using React hooks and Ruby on Rails to handle data request and response endpoints
- Deployed the project with Heroku and Netlify services providing more accessibility for the project
- Created a localStorage hook that persisted data and stored it for the user in the application
- Created a Postgres database to serve as the Rails API

Fantasy All-Stars - Github | Demo

Fantasy All-Stars lets you build custom rosters and compete for points with your friends

- Authorized user with JSON Web Tokens for client-side token handling adding additional security
- Built with React, React Bootstraps and Redux to store states throughout the application
- Created a Redux store for handling key states throughout the entire application
- Utilizing React bootstrap components to structure the layout of the application

TypeScript Weather App- Github | Website

The Weather App is a web application to check local weather conditions

- Incorporated TypeScript and React components to create a single page application
- Async and synchronous data storing with Openweather-API and fetch request
- Clean aesthetic with unique styling made with CSS and React Bootstraps

EXPERIENCE

Merck Rahway, NJ Senior Data Analyst 03/2019 - 07/2020

- Processed 100+ data packages and sensitive data reports adhering to deadlines
- Confirmed the integrity and transported 1000+ records in various media formats
- Decrypted and encrypted 100+ hard drives for our company's departments

Aculabs East Brunswick, NJ 08/2018 - 02/2019

Data Entry Specialist

- Responded promptly to all Urgent patient concerns whenever on call
- Processed and entered 100+ unstructured forms daily into a database
- Maintained the legitimacy of 1000+ database records

EDUCATION

Flatiron School New York, NY Full Stack Web Development 12/2020 - 04/2021

Rutgers University New Brunswick, NJ Bachelor of Arts in Information Technology 05/2019